Now, earlier in this lesson,
الآن، في هذا الدرس
we talked about project management tools to be
تحدثنا عن أدوات إدارة المشاريع
a key element used to communicate the project status to the client.
كعنصر رئيسي يستخدم لتوضيح حالة المشروع للعميل.
They also help in project planning and project timelines,
وهي تساعد أيضًا في تخطيط المشاريع والجداول الزمنية للمشروع،
as well as assigning tasks to different users.
فضلًا عن إسناد المهام لمستخدمين مختلفين.
Now, there are a lot of tools out there that
وهناك الكثير من الأدوات الأخرى التي
offer a variety of features for a variety of projects.
تقدم مجموعة متنوعة من المزايا لمجموعة متنوعة من المشاريع.
The advantage of most of these tools is that they are completely on the web,
وميزة معظم هذه الأدوات أنها كلها موجودة على الموقع الإلكتروني،
which means you do not need to install anything.
مما يعني أنك لن تحتاج إلى تثبيت أي شيء.
You can access it from any computer,
يمكنك الوصول إليها من أي كمبيوتر،
any new features are automatically installed and available to you and you
يتم تثبيت أي ميزات جديدة تلقائيًا وتكون متاحة لكم، وتستطيع
can share your work in project with any user just by entering their email.
مشاركة عملك في المشروع مع أي مستخدم عن طريق إدخال بريده الإلكتروني.
But let's look at some pros and cons of a project management tool and in
ولكن دعونا ننظر إلى بعض الإيجابيات والسلبيات لأدوات إدارة المشاريع،
what situations it is a good idea to use
والحالات التي يستحسن استخدام الأدوات فيها،
them and situations that it is not a good idea to use them.
والحالات التي لا يُفضل استخدامها فيها.
First, project management tools
أولًا، فإن أدوات إدارة المشاريع
definitely help us with managing complexities in the project.
بالتأكيد تساعدنا في إدارة الجوانب المعقدة للمشروع.
If there are too many moving parts,
في حال كان هناك الكثير من الأجزاء المتغيرة،
lots of different phases of the project,
أو العديد من المراحل المختلفة للمشروع،
long timelines, you may want to use
أو جداول زمنية طويلة، ففي هذه الحالات تحتاج لاستخدام
a sophisticated project management tool to manage all that complexity.
أداة متطورة لإدارة كل هذه التفاصيل والجوانب المعقدة للمشاريع.
Now, if there are many users working on the same project,
والآن إذا كان هناك العديد من المستخدمين يعملون على نفس المشروع،
it does make sense to use a proper tool for everyone to be on
فمن المنطقي استخدام أداة مناسبة لكي يكون الجميع على
the same page and for streamline status updates, etc.
اطلاع، ولتبسيط تحديث حالة المشروع، وما إلى ذلك.
Project management tools are, of course,
وأدوات إدارة المشاريع هي بالطبع
a communication tool, but they can be used for day-to-day communication as well.
أداة اتصال ولكن يمكن استخدامها في التواصل اليومي أيضًا.
Like you can tag people on specific tasks and leave comments.
فتستطيع الإشارة إلى أشخاص في مهام محددة وتترك تعليق.
You could start a quick chat with another user.
يمكنك بدء محادثة سريعة مع مستخدم آخر.
This may also help reduce or eliminate another communication channel within the company.
وقد يساعد ذلك أيضًا على الحد أو القضاء على وسائل الاتصال الأخرى داخل الشركة.
These tools can also help with setting timelines.
ويمكن أن تساعد هذه الأدوات أيضًا في تحديد جداول زمنية.
To liaise Gantt charts, for example,
فلتنسيق مخططات Gantt كمثال،
you can set reminders for when a deadline is approaching.
تستطيع وضع رسائل تذكير لموعد التسليم النهائي.
You can also set alerts for any unexpected activity in the project.
يمكنك أيضًا وضع تنبيهات لأي نشاط غير متوقع في المشروع.
On the other side, project management tools
وعلى الجانب الآخر، فأدوات إدارة المشاريع
generally take time to learn and get a handle on.
تحتاج منك وقت لتتعلمها وتُجيد التعامل معها.
This could be a blocker for users with low technical aptitude.
وقد يُمثل ذلك صعوبة أمام المستخدمين ذوي القدرات التقنية المنخفضة.
It could take up to a few months before a team in
قد يستغرق الأمر بضعة أشهر لفريق
a large project gets comfortable using a project management tool.
يعمل على مشروع كبير حتى يشعر بالراحة عند استخدام أدوات المشاريع.
Project management tools are also not a good fit for
كما أن أدوات إدارة المشاريع ليست مناسبة
projects where the overhead of the tool exceeds the benefits it provides.
للمشاريع التي تتجاوز فيها النفقات العامة للأداة الفوائد التي توفرها.
Some banks for small projects,
ففي بعض بنوك المشاريع الصغيرة،
the overhead of using a tool is much higher,
قد تكون النفقات العامة لاستخدام أداة أعلى بكثير
both in terms of cost and bang.
من حيث التكلفة و المجهود.
For those projects, a Google Sheet or maybe
فيناسب هذه المشاريع العمل بـ Google Sheet أو
a Google Doc may be sufficient for project communication.
العمل بـ Google Doc ويكون ذلك كافيًا للتواصل بشأن المشروع.